

Profile

Being an SRE is a means for me to interact with complex, dynamic, distributed systems. I have been gaining an interest in meta-technical issues regarding engineer interactions, culture, security, compliance and governance.

I see my job as being just as much, if not more, about communication with other engineers to smooth workflows and uncover hidden efficiencies as it is about technical expertise.

Employment History

Site Reliability Engineer, Cometh, Paris

FEBRUARY 2023 - OCTOBER 2023

Broad spectrum position with ownership of the whole infrastructure and automation tooling in a context of fast-paced feature delivery, incoming legal compliance constraints and security risks inherent to the crypto-currency industry.

The stack revolved around Docker, Kubernetes and GCP, with states managed through Terraform and CI/CD through Drone CI.

- Managed existing CI/CD pipelines and wrote new ones for containerized micro-services.
- Administered and managed the full life-cycle of multi-zonal Kubernetes clusters.
- Performance-tuned un-managed middle-ware (Nginx, Kafka, PostgreSQL, Drone CI etc.)
- Conceived complex network typologies across internal and external services.
- Significantly improved data collection, observability and alerting across the stack and its exploitation by the team.
- Normalized deployment configurations across the board.
- Managed various database typologies.
- Regularily reviewed the financial impact of our technical decisions.
- Performed failure recovery in the timely manner (including once during a
 presentation during a large conference), wrote relevant post-mortems and
 communicated with up-stream support and developpers regarding findings.
- Communicated on a constant basis with developpers to improve on our product goals.
- Lead the implementation of the cyber part of ISO27001 2022 within the company in view of being compliant with financial regulation.

DevOps Engineer, Fortil, Aix-en-Provence

JUNE 2022 - FEBRUARY 2023

Sent as a consultant to Docaposte, the IT branch of the French Postal services.

- Took ownership of several critical but poorly documented and understood Kubernetes clusters running old configurations with no stakeholder in the company. They were sanitized, updated, normalized and documented for later generations.
- Recovered from esoteric failure modes on said clusters in a timely manner.
- Improved on existing CI/CD practices.
- At times did various systems administration and middle-ware managment tasks.
 Managing and deploying Apache servers, fixing broken GlusterFS storage etc.

Details

Aix-en-Provence

France

0684828603

vincentloupmon+pro@protonmail.com

Links

Linkedin

Github

Skills

DevOps

SecOps

FinOps

Software Development

Document Writing

Advocacy and Communication

Languages

French

English

Hobbies

History, Linguistics, Cinema, Literature, Fashion, Vinyl Collecting, Music Making

Internships

Junior DevOps Engineer, Bitgen, Paris

JANUARY 2022 - APRIL 2022

I interned at a crypto-currency staking company, with the main task being containerizing and deploying on Kuberenetes Ethereum and Ethereum-adjacent micro-services, with a mind for security and availability.

Side tasks included redaction of educational content around crypto-currencies and filling in on web front and back development.

Education

Concepteur-Développeur d'Applications, AFPA, Brive-la-Gaillarde

MAY 2021 - APRIL 2022

Although self-taught since my early teenage years, I hadn't chosen IT as a career path until my late twenties. As such, to get started professionally, I chose a year-long training course centered about software application conception and development.

This included software design principles, practical C# development, modern web development with both client-side and server-side rendering, databse design principles and implementation and so on.